Register of the John Vaizey Papers, 1926-1985
Hoover Institution Archives
John Vaizey Papers
1926-1985
86017
Hoover Institution Archives
38 manuscript boxes, 4 envelopes, 2 phonotapes (16.4 linear feet)
Writings, correspondence, appointment books, printed matter, phonotapes, and photographs, relating to education in Great Britain and elsewhere; calculation of economic aspects of education; economic conditions in Great Britain; economic theory, especially the natures of capitalism and socialism; public support of the arts; contemporary British culture; and British politics.
Vaizey, John, 1929-
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1986.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1929, Oct. 1 Born, Greenwich, London, England
1951 M.A., Queens' College, Cambridge
1952-1953 United Nations, Geneva
1953-1956 Fellow, St. Catharine's College, Cambridge
1956-1960 University Lecturer, Oxford
1958 Author, The Costs of Education
1959 Author, Scenes from Institutional Life
1961 Author (with Patrick Lynch), Guinness's Brewery in the Irish Economy
1962 Author, The Economics of Education Author, Education for Tomorrow
1962-1966 Fellow and Tutor, Worcester College, Oxford
1963 Author, The Control of Education
1965 Editor, The Residual Factor and Economic Growth Editor, (with E.A.G. Robinson), The Economics of Education
1965-1972, 1978 Member, UNESCO National Committee
1966-1982 Professor of Economics, Brunel University
1967 Author, The Barometer Man Author, Education in the Modern World
1968 Author, The Sleepless Lunch Author (with John Sheehan), Resources for Education
1969-1971 Author (with colleagues), The Economics of Educational Costing
1970 Author, The Type to Succeed
1971 Author, Capitalism Author, Social Democracy
1972 Author, The Political Economy of Education
1973 Author (with Keith Norris), The Economics of Research and Technology
1974 Author, History of British Steel Editor, Economic Sovereignty and Regional Policy
1975 Editor, Whatever Happened to Equality?
1976 Author (with C.F.O. Clarke), Education: The State of the Debate
1976 Life Peer, Lord John Ernest Vaizey, Baron of Greenwich
1977 Author (with Keith Norris), Teach Yourself Economics
1980 Author, Capitalism and Socialism
1982-1984 Principal, St. Catharine's, Cumberland Lodge
1983 Author, The Squandered Peace Author, In Breach of Promise
1984 Author, The National Health
1984, July 19 Died, London, England
Arts.; British literature.; Capitalism.; Economics.; Economists.; Education--Economic aspects.; Education--Great Britain.; Education.; Great Britain--Civilization.; Great Britain--Economic conditions.; Great Britain--Politics and government--1945-; Great Britain.; Phonotapes.; Socialism.
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1946-1984. (Box 1-6)
  Scope and Contents note
  Clippings, correspondence and miscellany relating to the life of John Ernest Vaizey, Baron of Greenwich, arranged alphabetically by form.
- CORRESPONDENCE FILE, 1960-1984. (Box 7-14)
  Correspondence of Lord and Lady Vaizey, arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1951-1984. (Box 15-36)
  Drafts and printed copies of books, articles, clippings, correspondence, speeches, lectures, reports, radio broadcasts, drama, book reviews and background material. Arranged chronologically.
- SUBJECT FILE, 1926-1984. (Box 37-38)
  Clippings, correspondence, lists, press releases, reports, printed articles, transcripts and pamphlets relating to education, economics, British politics and government, Northern Ireland, UNESCO, and other subjects. Arranged alphabetically by subject.
- PHONOTAPES
- PHOTOGRAPHS.
  69 prints / 4 envelopes
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1946-1984
  - Address book (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1964-1984
    - General (Folder 2-17)
    - Death (Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, Letters to the Vaizey family upon Lord Vaizey's death, 1984.
    - General. Includes correspondence neither to nor from Vaizey family, lists of correspondents, obituary, printed programs, and holograph drafts by John Vaizey of programs for his funeral and memorial service (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified (Folder 2-3)
    - A-M (Folder 4-17)
    - N-Z (Box 3, Folder 1-12)
  - Diaries
    - 1946-1960 (Folder 13-14)
    - 1960-1979 (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
    - 1980-1984 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Dreams, Some make reference to Dr. M. Coghlan, 1977-1984.
    - Undated (Folder 2)
    - 1977-1984 (Folder 3-12)
  - Horoscopes
    - Includes correspondence with P. I. H. Taylor, astrologer, 1965-1969, 1965-1975. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - 1977-1983 (Folder 2)
  - Passports, 1955, 1962, 1972 (Folder 3)
  - Resumes
    - General. Curricula vitae for Lord and Lady John Vaizey (Folder 4)
    - Contemporary Authors (Folder 5)
    - Current Biography (Folder 6)
    - Dictionary of International Biography (Folder 7)
    - Dod's Parliamentary Companion (Folder 8)
    - International Biographical Centre (Folder 9)
    - Men of Achievement (Folder 10)
    - Who's Who (Folder 11)
    - Writers Directory (Folder 12)
  - Reminiscences
    - General. Notes used in the drafting of "Autobiography" (Folder 13)
    - "An Autobiographical Sequence," Outline, n.d. (Folder 14)
    - "John Vaizey: Emergence of a British Economist," International Social Sciences Journal, Printed Copy, 1973. (Folder 15)
    - "Autobiography," Early draft. Typescript, 1977. (Folder 16)
    - "Autobiography," Typescript, 1977. (Folder 17)
    - "Autobiography," Amended 1980. Typescript, 1977. (Folder 18)
    - "Autobiography," Amended 1983. Typescript, 1977. (Folder 19)
    - "What we Know about my Mother's Family," Annotated 1982. Typescript, 1979. (Folder 20)
    - "A History of My Own Life," Holograph, 1982. (Folder 21)
    - Essay, Relates to youth, 1984. (Folder 22)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1960-1984
  - General. Correspondence neither to nor from John Vaizey, 1977-1985 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Unidentified, 1963-1984 (Folder 2-3)
  - Abel-Smith, Lionel, n.d. (Folder 4)
  - Ablett, John F., 1976 (Folder 5)
  - Agnew, Dermot, 1984 (Folder 6)
  - Aiken, William, 1984 (Folder 7)
  - Aird, Sir Alistair, n.d. (Folder 8)
  - Airey of Abingdon, Baroness, 1980-1981 (Folder 9)
  - Allaway, P. A., 1976 (Folder 10)
  - American Enterprise Institute for Public Policy Research, 1982 (Folder 11)
  - Amis, Kingsley, 1963-1981 (Folder 12)
  - Anderson, W. E. K., 1983 (Folder 13)
  - Andry, R. G., 1976 (Folder 14)
  - Annan, Lord Noel. Includes correspondence with others and writings by Annan
    - n.d. (Folder 15)
    - 1971-1973 (Folder 16)
    - 1974-1984 (Folder 17)
  - Aprieto, Pacifico N., 1978 (Folder 18)
  - Arkin, Marc, 1976 (Folder 19)
  - Armitage, Sir Arthur, 1976 (Folder 20)
  - Armitage, Harry A., n.d. (Folder 21)
  - Azad, J. L., 1984 (Folder 22)
  - Bahri, A. M., 1980 (Folder 23)
  - Balfour, Honor, 1976 (Folder 24)
  - Ball-Wilson, H., 1976 (Folder 25)
  - Balls, Bryan, 1976 (Folder 26)
  - Banatvala, J. E., 1983 (Folder 27)
  - Bannister, Sir Roger, n.d. (Folder 28)
  - Barker, Alan, 1976 (Folder 29)
  - Barker, Anthony, Includes "Planning Inquiries: a role for Parliament," 1984 (Folder 30)
  - Barker, Theo, 1976 (Folder 31)
  - Barlow, Gillian, 1983 (Folder 32)
  - Barnes, M., 1980 (Folder 33)
  - Barnett, C. A., 1983 (Folder 34)
  - Bauer, Peter, 1984 (Folder 35)
  - Beer, Ian, 1976 (Folder 36)
  - Bell, Malcolm, 1984 (Folder 37)
  - Bellwin, Lord I., 1984 (Folder 38)
  - Belmont, M. J. K., 1984 (Folder 39)
  - Benn, Tony, 1967-1981 (Folder 40)
  - Bennett, Francis, 1976 (Folder 41)
  - Bentinck, Gaby, 1978 (Folder 42)
  - Bentley, W., 1978 (Folder 43)
  - Blake, Lord Robert, 1980 (Folder 44)
  - Blank, Justin de, 1976 (Folder 45)
  - Bodsworth, C., 1976 (Folder 46)
  - Bogdanor, V. B., n.d. (Folder 47)
  - Bosanquet, N., 1976 (Folder 48)
  - Bourget, Jean-Loup and Eithne, 1976 (Folder 49)
  - Bowen, Ian, 1976 (Folder 50)
  - Boyle, Lord E., 1975 (Folder 51)
  - Boyson, Rhodes, 1980 (Folder 52)
  - Bradford, Phoebe, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Bradley, William, 1978-1979 (Folder 2)
  - Bragg, S. L., Includes correspondence with A.J. Reynolds; House of Lords Official Report (Hansard), printed copy, 1979-1982. (Folder 3)
  - Briggs, Asa, 1976 (Folder 4)
  - Brinson, Peter, 1976-1981 (Folder 5)
  - British Council, Includes correspondence with Conor Cruise O'Brien, a British Council prospectus; curricula vitae and other materials relating to John Vaizey's application for the position of Director-General, 1979. (Folder 6)
  - British Irish Association, 1981 (Folder 7)
  - Brophy, Brigid, 1976 (Folder 8)
  - Brown, Alan, 1970-1976 (Folder 9)
  - Brown, Lord George, 1963-1976 (Folder 10)
  - Brown, Ian S., 1983-1984 (Folder 11)
  - Brownjohn, Alan, 1976 (Folder 12)
  - Brunel University, 1976-1984 (Folder 13)
  - Brunton, Gordon, 1983 (Folder 14)
  - Bryan, R. C. P., 1968-1972 (Folder 15)
  - Bulcher, M., n.d. (Folder 16)
  - Bull, George, 1984. Includes articles written by John Vaizey for Director (Folder 17)
  - Burgess, G. J., 1976 (Folder 18)
  - Burmingham, David, n.d. (Folder 19)
  - Burn, Colin M., 1980 (Folder 20)
  - Burnett, John, n.d. (Folder 21)
  - Burrows, N. F. Elliott, 1976 (Folder 22)
  - Bury, J. P. T., 1983 (Folder 23)
  - Callaghan, Rt. Hon. James, 1968-1977 (Folder 24)
  - Campbell, James, 1978-1980 (Folder 25)
  - Cannon, 1976 (Folder 26)
  - Carrington, Rt. Hon. Lord, 1978-1980 (Folder 27)
  - Carson, John C., 1982 (Folder 28)
  - Carter, C. F., 1977 (Folder 29)
  - Cave, M., 1976 (Folder 30)
  - Centre for Policy Studies, Includes prospectus, 1983-1984. (Folder 31)
  - Chalfont, Rt. Hon. Lord, 1977 (Folder 32)
  - Chalmers, Ray, Includes correspondence with others, 1983. (Folder 33)
  - Chandler, Kay, 1976 (Folder 34)
  - Chief, Bureau of Criminal Identification and Investigation, 1973 (Folder 35)
  - Ciechanowiecki, A. S., 1976 (Folder 36)
  - Cleland, David, 1984 (Folder 37)
  - Clark, William, n.d. (Folder 38)
  - Clarke, Mary, 1981 (Folder 39)
  - Clarke, Tony, 1980 (Folder 40)
  - Cobb, Peter, 1984 (Folder 41)
  - Cobb, Richard, 1977-1978 (Folder 42)
  - Coghlan, M., SEE ALSO: BIOGRAPHICAL FILE/Dreams, 1976-1983. (Folder 43)
  - Coles, E. K. Townsend, 1984 (Folder 44)
  - College of Preceptors, Includes "Education Today," 1981. Printed copy, 1981-1982. (Folder 45)
  - Colony Holidays, Includes prospectus, 1983-1984. (Folder 46)
  - Committee for the Free World, Includes membership list and statement, 1980-1981. (Folder 47)
  - Congdon, Tim, Includes "The Analytical Foundations of the Medium-Term Financial Strategy," 1984. (Folder 48)
  - Conservative and Unionist Central Office, Includes correspondence with Baroness Seear, 1981. (Folder 49)
  - Coombs, David, 1984 (Folder 50)
  - Copperman, F. L., 1984 (Folder 51)
  - Coppock, J. T., n.d. (Folder 52)
  - Cowan, L. D., Includes correspondence with others, 1983. (Folder 53)
  - Crabtree, G., 1984 (Folder 54)
  - Crank, John, 1976 (Folder 55)
  - Cranston, Maurice, n.d. (Folder 56)
  - Crawford, Mrs. Ian, 1983 (Folder 57)
  - Creamer, Brian, 1983 (Folder 58)
  - Crocker, W. R., 1986 (Folder 59)
  - Cropper, Peter, 1976 (Folder 60)
  - Crook, Arthur, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Crossman, Rt. Hon. Richard, 1962-1973 (Folder 2)
  - Crowther, Eric, 1980 (Folder 3)
  - Cuthbertson, Elona, 1976 (Folder 4)
  - Dance, Brian, 1976 (Folder 5)
  - Daniels, J., 1976 (Folder 6)
  - Davies, Bleddyn, 1976-1984 (Folder 7)
  - Davies, J. B., 1984 (Folder 8)
  - Davies, W. S., 1984 (Folder 9)
  - Davies, Richard, 1976 (Folder 10)
  - Dear, Mrs. Geoffrey, 1983 (Folder 11)
  - Deighton, Elizabeth, 1976 (Folder 12)
  - Denktash, President, 1984 (Folder 13)
  - Department of Health and Social Security, Includes notes and other materials relating to John Vaizey's claim for sickness benefit, 1981. (Folder 14)
  - Devlin, Keith, 1976 (Folder 15)
  - Dickinson, Peter, 1976-1980 (Folder 16)
  - Dimson, Gladys, 1976 (Folder 17)
  - Donnelly, Desmond, 1963-1968. Includes D. Donnelly, "The British Economy," speech, House of Commons, August 2, 1965, printed copy; review (by Dean Acheson) of D. Donnelly, "Struggle for the World," typescript; A. S. Parkes, "Biological Aspects of the Population Explosion," Advancement of Science, printed copy; correspondence with Dean Acheson, 1965, March 1965 (Folder 18)
  - Donnelly, Rosemary, Includes program for Desmond Donnelly's funeral, 1977-1980. (Folder 19)
  - Doubleday, Noel, 1984 (Folder 20)
  - Dow, C., 1976 (Folder 21)
  - Drake, F. J., 1976 (Folder 22)
  - Eatwell, John, 1976 (Folder 23)
  - Elizabeth II, Queen, 1982-1983 (Folder 24)
  - Elkan, Walter, n.d. (Folder 25)
  - Eurich, Alvin C., 1976 (Folder 26)
  - Evans, Colin, 1976 (Folder 27)
  - Evans, Harold, 1984 (Folder 28)
  - Falkender, Lady Marie, 1976-1982 (Folder 29)
  - Fallon, Ivan, 1984 (Folder 30)
  - Fanshaw, Lord, 1984 (Folder 31)
  - Fasler, J., 1983 (Folder 32)
  - Faulkener, R. A., 1984 (Folder 33)
  - Ferguson, James L., Includes program for General Foods Corporation dinner, 1983. (Folder 34)
  - Field, Frank, 1984 (Folder 35)
  - Fikri, Tansel, 1984 (Folder 36)
  - Financial Times, The Editor, 1983 (Folder 37)
  - Findlay, Paul, 1976 (Folder 38)
  - Finniston, Sir Montague, 1976 (Folder 39)
  - Fischer, George, n.d. (Folder 40)
  - Fischer, Harry, 1976 (Folder 41)
  - Flemming, L.?, 1976 (Folder 42)
  - Ford, Boris, 1976 (Folder 43)
  - Foskett, Douglas, 1976 (Folder 44)
  - Foulkes, Nigel, 1976 (Folder 45)
  - Foxcroft, Robert G. B., 1976 (Folder 46)
  - Fowler, Rt. Hon. Norman, 1984 (Folder 47)
  - Frankel, H., 1980 (Folder 48)
  - Franks, Lord Oliver and Lady Barbara, 1962-1980 (Folder 49)
  - Gainsborough, 1980 (Folder 50)
  - Gaitskell, Dora, 1973 (Folder 51)
  - Gaitskell, Hugh, 1960-1962 (Folder 52)
  - Galloway, David, 1884 (Folder 53)
  - Garrison, Arthur, Includes various articles by others, 1980. (Folder 54)
  - Gat, E., 1973 (Folder 55)
  - Gibbons, G. W., 1980 (Folder 56)
  - Gibson, Pat, 1976 (Folder 57)
  - Gillett, J. D., 1976 (Folder 58)
  - Glendevon, Rt. Hon. Lord, 1976 (Folder 59)
  - Gombos, Laszlo, 1983. Includes letter to the editor of The Times (Folder 60)
  - Gordon-Potts, Peter, 1976 (Folder 61)
  - Goronwy-Roberts, Rt. Hon Lord, 1976-1979 (Folder 62)
  - Gould, J., 1983 (Folder 63)
  - Gould, S. J., 1980 (Folder 64)
  - Gow, Ian, 1983 (Folder 65)
  - Graham, A., 1970 (Folder 66)
  - Graham-Jones, M. J., 1979 (Folder 67)
  - Grant, Patrick, 1976 (Folder 68)
  - Grayson Travel Limited, 1979 (Folder 69)
  - Greentree, W. W. C., 1984 (Folder 70)
  - Gregory-Hood, A. M. H., 1976 (Folder 71)
  - Greve-in-Chianti, Goodman, 1976 (Folder 72)
  - Grimond, Rt. Hon. Jo, 1976 (Folder 73)
  - Grimond, Laura, 1978 (Folder 74)
  - Guildhall School of Music and Drama, Includes prospectus, clippings, notes, curriculum vitae and other materials relating to John Vaizey's application for the post of Principal, 1978. (Folder 75)
  - Gulbenkian Foundation, Includes memoranda and pamphlet relating to the Foundation and John Vaizey's tenure as Chairman, 1975-1981. (Folder 76)
  - Hablan, Peter, 1977-1978. Includes an article by Teddy Kollek, "Jerusalem," Foreign Affairs, offprint, July, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Hackley, Victor S., 1976 (Folder 2)
  - Hall, A. J., 1984 (Folder 3)
  - Halsbury, n.d. (Folder 4)
  - Hannam?, Michael, n.d. (Folder 5)
  - Harcourt, Scott?, 1976 (Folder 6)
  - Harland, Robin, 1983 (Folder 7)
  - Harlech, Rt. Hon Lord David, 1976 (Folder 8)
  - Harris, Frances, 1976 (Folder 9)
  - Harris of High Cross, Rt. Hon. Lord, 1980 (Folder 10)
  - Harrod, Lady Billa, 1984 (Folder 11)
  - Harrods, Accounts Department, 1984 (Folder 12)
  - Harvey, Martin, 1976 (Folder 13)
  - Haverland, G. (Folder 14)
  - Haycraft, Colin, 1976 (Folder 15)
  - Heath, Rt. Hon. Edward, Includes John Vaizey, "Manpower Planning," manuscript and an untitled and undated speech by Edward Heath relating to education, 1965-1975. (Folder 16)
  - Heim, Archbishop Bruno B., 1981 (Folder 17)
  - Heller, M. A., 1980 (Folder 18)
  - Hemily, Philip W., 1984 (Folder 19)
  - Hennessey, Peter, 1984 (Folder 20)
  - Herbert, David, 1976 (Folder 21)
  - Hermon, Sir John, 1984 (Folder 22)
  - Hibbert, Reginald, Includes newsletters from the Ditchley Foundation, 1984. (Folder 23)
  - Hill, J. R., 1984 (Folder 24)
  - Hobbow?, Eric, n.d. (Folder 25)
  - Hobkirk, Michael, 1976 (Folder 26)
  - Hollister, R. G., 1964-1977 (Folder 27)
  - Horlock, John, Includes Open University materials, 1984. (Folder 28)
  - Hosier, John, 1981 (Folder 29)
  - House, Richard, n.d. (Folder 30)
  - Howard, Billy, 1976 (Folder 31)
  - Howard, David, 1966 (Folder 32)
  - Howard, Robin, 1976 (Folder 33)
  - Howarth, T. E. B., 1976-1982 (Folder 34)
  - Howe, Rt. Hon. Sir Geoffrey, Includes an untitled, undated lecture fragment by Sir Geoffrey Howe, 1975-1980. (Folder 35)
  - Hubbard, Geoffrey, 1976 (Folder 36)
  - Hudaverdi, Munur H., 1984 (Folder 37)
  - Institute for Policy Research, 1984 (Folder 38)
  - Isaacs, Jeremy, 1976 (Folder 39)
  - Jackson, Joseph, 1983 (Folder 40)
  - James, Canon Eric, Includes correspondence with others; clippings; printed matter of a religious nature, 1965-1979. (Folder 41)
  - Jenkins, Rt. Hon. Roy, 1966-1983 (Folder 42)
  - Jenkins, Simon, 1974 (Folder 43)
  - Jenkinson, Ronnie, 1974 (Folder 44)
  - Johnson, Adrian, 1976 (Folder 45)
  - Johnson, Marigold, 1976 (Folder 46)
  - Jones, Pryce, 1976 (Folder 47)
  - Jones, Walter, 1976 (Folder 48)
  - Joseph, Rt. Hon. Sir Keith, Includes a printed copy of a lecture by Keith Joseph, "Monetarism is not Enough," lecture, 1976, printed copy, 1962-1964. (Folder 49)
  - Kahana, Hannah and Fred, 1978-1979 (Folder 50)
  - Kaldon, Lord N., 1976 (Folder 51)
  - Keir, Malcolm, 1984 (Folder 52)
  - Kempner, Thomas, 1976 (Folder 53)
  - Kendall, Anne and Fred, 1976 (Folder 54)
  - Kennedy, Vain and Patricia, 1976 (Folder 55)
  - Kertan?, George, 1974 (Folder 56)
  - King, John, 1976 (Folder 57)
  - Kollek, Teddy, 1977-1978 (Folder 58)
  - Koray, Ozer, 1983-1984 (Folder 59)
  - Kraft?, John, 1976 (Folder 60)
  - Kramer, A., 1984 (Folder 61)
  - Laffin, John, 1976 (Folder 62)
  - Lancaster, Ian, 1980 (Folder 63)
  - Lauwerys, Joseph, 1976 (Folder 64)
  - Lawson, Nigel, 1983 (Folder 65)
  - Layton, Hon. David, 1976 (Folder 66)
  - Lee, Sir Desmond (Folder 67)
  - Lestor, Joan, 1973 (Folder 68)
  - Lever, Harold, 1976 (Folder 69)
  - Levin, Bernard, 1980-1981 (Folder 70)
  - Levy, John D. A., 1972-1981 (Folder 71)
  - Longford, Lord, 1976-1982 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Loram, D. A., 1976 (Folder 2)
  - Loslett?, Peter, 1976 (Folder 3)
  - Lucas, Eric, 1978-1979 (Folder 4)
  - Ludvigsen, Karl, 1983 (Folder 5)
  - Lunt, James G., 1980-1981 (Folder 6)
  - Luz, A. J., 1979 (Folder 7)
  - Lynch, Patrick, Includes clippings; correspondence from others, 1964-1983. (Folder 8)
  - Lynner, Halfdan, 1980 (Folder 9)
  - Lyons, Raymond, 1967-1981 (Folder 10)
  - McAlpine, Lord R. Alistair, n.d. (Folder 11)
  - MacArthur, Brian and Bridget, 1976-1984 (Folder 12)
  - McCormack, Richard, 1984 (Folder 13)
  - McCrone, Gavin, 1976 (Folder 14)
  - McEvoy, Sir Theodore, 1980 (Folder 15)
  - Mackintosh, John P., 1976 (Folder 16)
  - Maclennan, Robert, 1983 (Folder 17)
  - Macleod, Rt. Hon. Iain, 1968-1970 (Folder 18)
  - Macrae, Norman, 1984 (Folder 19)
  - Macuab, Roy, n.d. (Folder 20)
  - Magno, Melecio, 1978 (Folder 21)
  - Maclure, S., n.d. (Folder 22)
  - Manduell, T., 1976 (Folder 23)
  - Manley, Roy, n.d. (Folder 24)
  - Mansfield, Earl of, 1984 (Folder 25)
  - Marcos, Imelda and Ferdinand E., 1977-1979 (Folder 26)
  - Markham, J., 1981 (Folder 27)
  - Margaret, Princess, 1983-1984 (Folder 28)
  - Maroni, David, 1976-1984 (Folder 29)
  - Marsh, John, Includes a clipping, 1976. (Folder 30)
  - Marsland, David, 1983 (Folder 31)
  - Martell, Dolores, 1983 (Folder 32)
  - Mason, Sir John C. M., 1978-1979 (Folder 33)
  - Masterman, Sir John, 1976 (Folder 34)
  - Maxwell, Robert, 1976 (Folder 35)
  - May, D., n.d. (Folder 36)
  - May, John, 1976 (Folder 37)
  - Menduina, Antonio, 1981 (Folder 38)
  - Menzies, Victor, 1976 (Folder 39)
  - Metcalfe, P.C., 1980 (Folder 40)
  - Metropolitan Police, Public Carriage Office, 1984 (Folder 41)
  - Meyers, Fred, 1976 (Folder 42)
  - Midwinter, S., 1984 (Folder 43)
  - Miller, Dan, 1976 (Folder 44)
  - Mills, Dame Margaret, n.d. (Folder 45)
  - Ministerio de Educacion y Ciencia, Orden Civil de Alfonso X El Sabio, 1969 (Folder 46)
  - Mitchell, David, 1972-1981 (Folder 47)
  - Mitchell, Derek, 1976 (Folder 48)
  - Mitchley, Mrs. M., 1984 (Folder 49)
  - Moffat, G. F., 1984 (Folder 50)
  - Monahan, James, 1981 (Folder 51)
  - Monteith, Charles, 1976 (Folder 52)
  - Moore, John, 1983 (Folder 53)
  - Morris, Norman, 1984 (Folder 54)
  - Moser, Sir Claus, 1981 (Folder 55)
  - Mottistone, Lord, 1980-1983 (Folder 56)
  - Moyne, Lord B., Includes clippings and correspondence with others, 1969-1980. (Folder 57)
  - Muftizade, O. F., 1984 (Folder 58)
  - Muhammad, Seyid, n.d. (Folder 59)
  - Mulley, Rt. Hon. F., 1977 (Folder 60)
  - Munir, Kemal, 1984 (Folder 61)
  - Murdoch, Rupert, 1981 (Folder 62)
  - Myerson, A. L., n.d. (Folder 63)
  - Nakpil, Carmen Guerrero, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - National Health Service, Includes correspondence with various departments within the Health Service, as well as with Margaret Thatcher, 1983-1984. (Folder 2)
  - Nestel, Stephanie, 1976 (Folder 3)
  - Nicholson, J. L., 1984 (Folder 4)
  - Nicolson, Sir David, 1983 (Folder 5)
  - Nissel, M., 1976 (Folder 6)
  - Noel, Mrs. Gerard, 1984 (Folder 7)
  - Norris, W. K., n.d. (Folder 8)
  - North Thames Gas Board, 1970-1983 (Folder 9)
  - Oakes, Gordon, 1977 (Folder 10)
  - O'Brien, Conor Cruise, 1983 (Folder 11)
  - O'Brien, George, Includes an obituary by John Vaizey, clipping, and a printed article by George O'Brien, "Het Droombeeld van de Overvloed," n.d., 1965-1983. (Folder 12)
  - Ogilvie, R. M., 1976? (Folder 13)
  - O'Mahony, David, 1976 (Folder 14)
  - Opie, Ragen, 1976 (Folder 15)
  - Ormian, Haim, 1966-1967 (Folder 16)
  - Owen, David, 1977-1983 (Folder 17)
  - Parker, Peter, 1976 (Folder 18)
  - Pasternak, C. A., 1976 (Folder 19)
  - Patten, John, 1983-1984 (Folder 20)
  - Paz, Justo de la, 1977 (Folder 21)
  - Peaker, Mrs. G. F., 1980 (Folder 22)
  - Pearson, P. J., 1976 (Folder 23)
  - Pegler. (see Correspondence File, Spicer)
  - Perfecto, Waldo, 1976-1980 (Folder 24)
  - Perkins, James A., 1976 (Folder 25)
  - Peters, A. F., 1976 (Folder 26)
  - Peterson, A., n.d. (Folder 27)
  - Phillips, Lawrence D., n.d. (Folder 28)
  - Pilkington, Eve and Godfrey, 1976 (Folder 29)
  - Pitt, Harry, 1976-1980 (Folder 30)
  - Playfair, Eddie, 1976 (Folder 31)
  - Playford, Mrs. S. B., 1984 (Folder 32)
  - Plummer, C. R., 1984 (Folder 33)
  - Police Courts of the Metropolis, 1961 (Folder 34)
  - Pollinger, Murray, 1980 (Folder 35)
  - Ponsonby, Tom, 1976 (Folder 36)
  - Pool, Edward, 1984 (Folder 37)
  - Pool, John, n.d. (Folder 38)
  - Popplewell, Mrs. O. B., n.d. (Folder 39)
  - Porter, James F., 1976 (Folder 40)
  - Porter, R., 1984 (Folder 41)
  - Powell, Anthony, 1966-1978 (Folder 42)
  - Powell, Rt. Hon. J. Enoch, 1972-1980 (Folder 43)
  - Prentice, Reg, 1975-1981 (Folder 44)